There are several types of IPv6 addresses
to know about for the exam and understanding
what types of addresses you have and can work
with when using IPv6.
I have run ipconfig on this device, and right
away, I see two types of IPv6 addresses.
The one that starts with 2601 is a global
unicast address.
Global unicast addresses usually start with
either a 2 or a 3.
A global unicast address in IPv6 is equivalent
to a public IPv4 address.
A unique local IPv6 address starts with an
FC or an FD.
Those are public IPv6 addresses as well, but
they are only routable within a single domain.
The other common IPv6 address we see is a
link-local address.
A link-local IPv6 address starts with FE80.
These are fairly equivalent to a private IPv4
address in that these addresses can communicate
with other devices on a local network.
Still, technically these addresses are most
similar to the IPv4 APIPA addresses, which
start with 169.254.